# Robbie Mackay

# Software Developer & Engineering Leader

+64 275762243 Auckland, New Zealand rm@robbiemackay.com

A thoughtful technical leader with over 10 years experience building successful web applications, with a focus on nonprofits and companies that make the world a better place. I thrive in a passionate collaborative team, driven by users needs and with freedom to make things better.

# Experience

## Basis - Lead Developer

2019 - Present. Remote

Basis is an early stage startup working on a new model for mental health. I joined as the second developer.

- Implemented a minimal agile dev process, metrics, and continuous delivery pipeline for fast, high quality releases, with increased visibility.
- Launched on-demand video coaching product.
- Optimized booking process leading to 4x increase in conversions.
- Improved matching of clients to specialists to reduce unfulfilled sessions.
- Supported and mentored other developers.

Python, PostgreSQL, Javascript, Redis, Celery, Heroku.

#### Ushahidi - CTO

2015 - 2018. Remote

Ushahidi is an open-source crowdsourcing platform to collect, manage, visualize, and respond to data from marginalized people or people in crisis situations.

- Led and mentored a distributed development team, building an open, collaborative and engaged culture.
- Grew the dev team from 5 to 10 developers spread across 6 countries.
- Moved the dev team to a sustainable agile dev process. Resulting in shorter, more predictable time to release, closer integration with product and design, and a more stable product.
- Led migration from a legacy software stack and infrastructure to modern replacements. Resulting in faster, more stable development, and reduced infrastructure costs.
- Created a long term plan to iteratively reduce technical debt, improve architecture and tooling while continuing to deliver value to product teams.

PHP, Laravel, Kohana, Javascript, React, AngularJS, Python, MySQL, RabbitMQ, Ansible, Terraform.

#### **Ushahidi** – Senior Developer

2012 - 2015, Remote

I joined Ushahidi in 2012 to lead development of client projects. In 2014 I led development of a new iteration of Ushahidi software.

- Led the rebuild of Ushahidi's open-source crowdsourcing tool.
- Launched SaaS edition of Ushahidi based on our open-source product.
- Technical contact and lead developer on client projects.
- Working within and improving an existing legacy code base over time.
- Deployed, managed and monitored infrastructure for client projects.

PHP, Laravel, Kohana, Javascript, AngularJS, Python, MySQL, RabbitMQ, Ansible.

# Torchbox - Drupal Web Developer

2010 - 2011. Oxford, UK

Torchbox is a digital agency building websites and application for people trying to make the world a better place.

- Developed complex Drupal based sites for charities and nonprofits.
- Scaling and optimising complex Drupal sites through a combination of static caching (with varnish and nginx) and improved app level caching.
- Building tools for fast, standardised development and deployment.

PHP, Drupal, Javascript, Python, MySQL, Sass, HTML, CSS.

## Greenpeace New Zealand - Web Developer

2009 - 2010. Auckland, NZ

Joined Greenpeace NZ in 2009 as their first full time developer, initially focussed on supporting a large online campaign around climate change.

- Developed multiple web applications and websites.
- Managing websites and social media feeds during high traffic live events.
- Deployed and optimized online fundraising tools for increased donations.
- Security testing and fixes on legacy web apps.

PHP, Drupal, Silverstripe, Javascript, HTML, CSS, MySQL, PostgreSQL.

#### Freelance - Web Developer

2002 - 2009

Worked as a freelance web developer part time while studying and then full time for a year. Developed a range of websites and applications for small businesses.

PHP, Silverstripe, Javascript, HTML + CSS.

## **Education**

**University of Auckland** – Bachelor of Engineering (Computer Systems)

Graduated 2009